<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> Smirnova M.A.</title>
    <link>https://smirnovamaria.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://smirnovamaria.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description> Smirnova M.A.</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 14:44:13 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://smirnovamaria.github.io/img/myphoto.jpg</url>
      <title> Smirnova M.A.</title>
      <link>https://smirnovamaria.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidents and patterns in nature</title>
      <link>https://smirnovamaria.github.io/post/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 14:44:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://smirnovamaria.github.io/post/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;essay-on-the-concept-of-modern-natural-science&#34;&gt;essay on the concept of modern natural science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important problem in modern natural science is the ratio of accidents and laws in nature. We can talk about this problem as a matter of chaos and self-order. This issue has been considered closely in science relatively recently, but chaos theory already occupies a leading position in the scientific environment.
The Newtonian picture of the world was an ordered structure of physical laws. It can also be called deterministic - all phenomena need to be explained and the causes of appearance or manifestation established. But over time, with the development of science, it became clear that not all phenomena obey our usual physical laws.
The simplest way to study is idealization. It is always easier to consider the right objects, to develop concepts for them. Therefore, mathematicians have always sought to reduce calculations to even straight, regular circles and triangles. But our world does not consist of perfect figures. You will not see a stone in the shape of an ideal ball, a mountain that is a cone or even structure of sand dunes in the desert. The real picture of our world cannot be idealized.
However, despite the complex structure of the world around us, in the first place they always sought to answer questions about man. As a set of simple atoms, it was able to form such a complex structure as a person. No mathematical equation could describe this process. Here, for the first time, the concept of self-ordering arose. Considering the phenomenon of morphogenesis, scientists wondered how cells understand which one becomes the skin and which, say, the eye. After all, at the beginning of the formation of the embryo there is not even any center capable of &amp;ldquo;giving orders.&amp;rdquo; This process brought to a standstill the science formed over the years.
The outstanding scientist Alan Turing is one of the first to try to describe such processes with mathematical equations. In particular, he was able to explain the formation of color in animals. This connection of mathematics and biology served as the beginning of the most important discoveries.
So, those phenomena that used to be considered subject to random fluctuations, we can describe with the help of equations? Does this mean that there are structured natural laws? These questions found their answers in chaos theory, one of the outstanding scientists in which was Edward Lawrence.
She finally answers the main question posed at the beginning of the essay. How are strict physical laws and random phenomena interconnected. In fact, order and disorder, stability and instability are of the same nature. We are used to considering chaos a manifestation of the unpredictability of our world. However, chaos is sometimes more predictable than our usual phenomena. Here you can mention the butterfly effect. Can the rise of butterfly wings in Brazil cause tornadoes in London? This absurd statement served as the beginning of a new understanding of the causal relationships between phenomena. Finding reasons can get us very far. However, this confirms the existence of chaotic laws.
In summary, we are still very far from fully understanding our world. However, the departure from determinism served as the backdrop of a big breakthrough in this area. The connection of laws and accidents is now more clearly felt than ever. And further study of nature and man cannot continue without this truth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
